[
  {
    "id": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following is a popular front-end development framework maintained by Google?",
    "option":["React","Angular","Vue.Js","Django"],
    "answer": "Angular"
  },
  {
    "id": "2",
    "question": "javascript and java are same language true or false?",
    "option": ["true","false"],
    "answer": "false"
  },
  {
    "id": "3",
    "question": "Which of the following is used to store and query data in a tabular format in web development?",
    "option":["Database","API","JSON","XML"],
    "answer": "database"
  },
  {
    "id": "4",
    "question": "Which of the following is a server-side scripting language commonly used for web development?",
    "option":["HTML","CSS","Python","Javascript"],
    "answer": "Python"
  },
  {
    "id": "5",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the “form” element in HTML?",
    "option":["It defines a hyperlink","It creates a container for metadata","It allows users to input data and submit it to the server","It defines a section in a document"],
    "answer": "It allows users to input data and submit it to the server"
  },
  {
    "id": "6",
    "question": "Which JavaScript function is used to change the content of an HTML element?",
    "option":["modify()","change()","update()","innerHTML()"],
    "answer": "InnerHTML"
  },
  {
    "id": "7",
    "question": "Which HTTP method is typically used to retrieve data from a web server?",
    "option":["GET","POST","PUT","DELETE"],
    "answer": "GET"
  },
  {
    "id": "8",
    "question": "Which HTML tag is used to define a table in web development?",
    "option":["{table}","{div}","{form}","{img}"],
    "answer": "{table}"
  },
  {
    "id": "9",
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of a front-end web development framework/library?",
    "option":["Express.js","Django","Flask","React.js"],
    "answer": "React.js"
  },
  {
    "id": "10",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the “cookie” in web development?",
    "option":["To store data on the client’s browser for future use","To encrypt sensitive information during transmission","To handle server-side logic","To create user authentication systems"],
    "answer": "To store data on the client’s browser for future use"
  },
  {
    "id": "11",
    "question": "What does the acronym “REST” stand for in the context of web development?",
    "option":["Representational State Transfer","Responsive Elements for Seamless Transition","Readable Element Style Transfer","Real-time Server Technology"],
    "answer": "Representational State Transfer"
  },
  {
    "id": "12",
    "question": "Which CSS property is used to create rounded corners for an HTML element?",
    "option":["border-radius","corner-radius","rounded-corners","box-radius"],
    "answer": "border-radius"
  },
  {
    "id": "13",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the “alt” attribute in an  tag?",
    "option":["It specifies the alignment of the image","It provides alternative text if the image fails to load","It sets the size of the image","It defines the image source"],
    "answer": "It provides alternative text if the image fails to load"
  },
  {
    "id": "14",
    "question": "Which HTML tag is used to create a hyperlink?",
    "option":["{a}","{link}","{h1}","{p}"],
    "answer": "{a}"
  },
  {
    "id": "15",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the script tag in HTML?",
    "option":["To define the page’s structure","To include external CSS styles","To include external JavaScript code","To create hyperlinks"],
    "answer": "To include external JavaScript code"
  },
  {
    "id": "16",
    "question": "Which part of web development is responsible for handling data storage and retrieval?",
    "option":["Front-end development","Back-end development","Full-stack development","Middleware development"],
    "answer": "Back-end development"
  },
  {
    "id": "17",
    "question": "_____ is NOT a popup message in javascript?",
    "option":["prompt","confirm","alert","Error"],
    "answer": "Error"
  },
  {
    "id": "18",
    "question": ".NET Framework was designed and developed by ______",
    "option":["Microsoft","IBM","Oracle","Google"],
    "answer": "Microspft"
  },
  {
    "id": "19",
    "question": "What does CORS stand for in web development?",
    "option":["Cross-Origin Resource Sharing","Cross-Object Resource Security","Content-Origin Resource Sharing","Client-Origin Resource System"],
    "answer": "Cross-Origin Resource Sharing"
  },
  {
    "id": "20",
    "question": "In a RESTful API, which HTTP method is typically used to update an existing resource?",
    "option":["GET","POST","PUT","DELETE"],
    "answer": "PUT"
  },
  {
    "id": "21",
    "question": "In a full-stack application, which tool is typically used for managing environment variables?",
    "option":["dotenv","express-session","mongoose","webpack"],
    "answer": "dotenv"
  },
  {
    "id": "22",
    "question": "What does the acronym API  stand for?",
    "option":["Application Programming Interface","Application Protocol Interface","Advanced Programming Interface","Application Process Integration"],
    "answer": "Application Programming Interface"
  },
  {
    "id": "23",
    "question": "What was JavaScript originally called when it was first released?",
    "option":["java","Netscape","Mocha","LiveScript"],
    "answer": "LiveScript"
  },
  {
    "id": "24",
    "question": "In JavaScript, which method iterates over the elements of an array and creates a new array based on the results of the function specified within said method?",
    "option":["map()","reverse()","split()","concat()"],
    "answer": "map()"
  },
  {
    "id": "25",
    "question": "In JavaScript, what is the name of the method used to remove white space from the beginning and end of a string?",
    "option":[".reduce()",".slice()",".trim()",".substring()"],
    "answer": "InnerHTML"
  }
]
